{
    "id": "231750e8ea0f415eb1c59ad913102d0a",
    "title": "General Grammar Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I would have been in bad trouble if she ………………….. me.",
            "description": "In the third conditional we use a past perfect tense in the if-clause and would have + past participle in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "didn't help",
                "hadn't helped",
                "wouldn't help"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "1f2aa564ddbf4214ab9c151bb5c41c82"
        },
        {
            "question": "Would you mind getting ……………… my foot?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "from",
                "of",
                "off"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "4f4520e1004245caace7d0e548c4e28c"
        },
        {
            "question": "You can take anything you …………………..",
            "description": "When both clauses refer to the future, we use a present tense in the subordinate clause to refer to future. ",
            "answers": [
                "find",
                "will find",
                "would find"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "0b09040488b9458885636f0ed40dcf08"
        },
        {
            "question": "I knew she ………………….. arrive before long.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, the verb in the subordinate clause too will be in the past tense. ",
            "answers": [
                "will",
                "would",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "09cd65e5c6864d44b25c0be0111a038e"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………. she drove, she could not catch them.",
            "description": "Fronted adjectives/adverbs are possible in a structure with as or though.",
            "answers": [
                "Fast though",
                "Fast as",
                "Though fast"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "c04453fea93c49aa8b62ba8f15eb3440"
        },
        {
            "question": "The picnic was ……………………..",
            "description": "Fun usually goes after is.",
            "answers": [
                "fun",
                "funny"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "aec4fb04fdba44b0813466c246587f29"
        },
        {
            "question": "Only after her death …………………….. able to understand her.",
            "description": "Inversion is used when a sentence starts with only or hardly or seldom.",
            "answers": [
                "I was",
                "was I"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "b89657ce2b844476978a478a92b5be08"
        },
        {
            "question": "Hardly …………………… arrived when trouble started.",
            "description": "Inversion is used when a sentence starts with only or hardly or seldom.",
            "answers": [
                "I had",
                "had I",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "4b595ecc31754ad5811cb1cb50cf7308"
        },
        {
            "question": "‘I don’t like salmon.’ ‘……………….. do I.’",
            "description": "After a negative statement, we can add another negative statement with neither/nor.",
            "answers": [
                "So",
                "Neither",
                "Either"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d4efb805e4fc4ff7a1efcaa1bc00b40d"
        },
        {
            "question": "As soon as they heard the gun shot, the birds …………………… away.",
            "description": "Flew is the past tense of fly.",
            "answers": [
                "flew",
                "flowed",
                "flown"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "be3fc8f91bae40f9805cbec6d09be57e"
        },
        {
            "question": "Those who know the answer should …………………… their hand.",
            "description": "Rise is intransitive raise is transitive. ",
            "answers": [
                "rise",
                "raise"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "44627447a38c4edc8b1de17df3a1f204"
        },
        {
            "question": "That is the last message he ……………………… from me.",
            "description": "Present and future tenses are possible after this is the last...",
            "answers": [
                "gets",
                "will get",
                "get"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "3cc45614178c4b8abc4d099d1df484e7"
        }
    ]
}